## **CHRIS KOBERSTINE**

Lake Wales, FL 33853

Phone: 813-347-1417 | Email: koberstine@hotmail.com LinkedIn:https://www.linkedin.com/in/chris-koberstine-754782a4/

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/koberstine/">https://github.com/koberstine/</a>
Portfolio: <a href="https://koberstine.github.io/profile/">https://koberstine.github.io/profile/</a>

#### **SUMMARY**

Full stack developer and U.S. Army veteran with experience in computer/network support and customer service. Recently earned a certificate in full stack development from the University of Central Florida. Skills in JavaScript, CSS and MERN stack (MongoBD, Express.js, Node.js and React.js). With a goal to employ clean and organized code and self-commenting naming conventions to build responsive applications that are easy for other developers and team members to integrate. Excited to leverage my skills as part of a fast-paced, quality-driven team to create applications solving real-world problems and delivering an outstanding user experience.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript ES6+, CSS, HTML, SQL, NoSQL, GraphQL

Applications: GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL

Tools: Express, React, Node, Handlebars, Query, Bootstrap

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **Redux Store**

https://github.com/koberstine/redux-store/

https://murmuring-brushlands-08289.herokuapp.com/

- A migration of an eCommerce application to Redux for managing State globally
- MongoDB, Express, Node, React, Redux

#### **Budget Tracker**

https://github.com/koberstine/budget-tracker/https://limitless-inlet-80650.herokuapp.com/

- Conversion of a budget tracking application to a Pogressive Web Application
- MongoDB, Express, Node, React, Redux, IndexedDB, Service Worker, manifest.ison

#### Share Thought

https://github.com/koberstine/share-thought/

https://vast-shore-81150.herokuapp.com/

- Back-end for a social network that allows users to create thoughts, react to thoughts and add other users as friends
- MongoDB, Express, Node, JavaScript, NoSQL
- Social network API uses entry points /api/users and /api/thoughts

.

# **KOBERSTINE**

#### **EDUCATION**

Bootcamp Certificate: University of Central Florida, Orlando, FL

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Associate in Science in Systems Analysis: Hillsborough Community College, Tampa, FL

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# MasTec Advanced Technologies Satellite Technician

Lake Wales, FL 2018 to 2020

- Installed, maintained and upgraded satellite television service.
- Provided knowledgeable responses on general and account specific information to customer inquiries in a courteous and professional manner.
- Utilized standard technology such as telephone, e-mail, and web browser to perform job duties.
- Completed service logs related to maintenance, installation and customer interactions.
- Performed troubleshooting, maintenance and repair to resolve issues with existing installations.
- Maintained regular and predictable attendance.

## General Dynamics Information Technology

Riverview, FL 2017 to 2018

- Customer Service Representative
  - Provided accurate and knowledgeable responses to telephone inquiries in a courteous and professional manner.
  - Maintained a current understanding of the Program's standard operating procedures, processes and Program policies.
  - Followed established and documented policies and standard operating procedures such as filling out timesheets, adhering to privacy rules and responding to phone inquiries.
  - Assisted callers with online inquiries and/or complaints.

#### The Diversity Initiative, Inc.

Tampa, FL

### **Employment Technician**

2011 to 2016

- Conducted online searches and research to identify potential employers.
- Maintained and updated databases of client records, employers and support activities.
- Implemented use of file sharing for frequently needed documents.
- Assisted in employment readiness and job placement for over 200 clients.
- Trained new employees on use of software, procedures and best practices.

## Bank of America, N.A.

Tampa, FL

#### Senior Specialist III

9/2004 to 7/2010

- Verified callers according to high-risk standards for access to financial accounts.
- Resolved escalation requests from customers and associates.
- Supervised on-the-job training for more than 100 associates.
- Maintained over 90% customer satisfaction rating.
- Trained escalation team on monthly updates to business procedures and software.
- Bank of America Spirit Medallion for outstanding customer service.